In this video, I'll be talking about structures.
I'll explain what they are, how to define, create, and access data within structures,
and a little bit about anonymous structures.
Structures allow data to be stored in groups.
These are similar to a class in other programming languages.
Each data point in the structure is called a field, and storing data in groups is usually
more efficient than storing them on their own, both for running your program and for
reading or writing your code.
It is possible to associate functionality with structures, sort of like writing a method
for a class, which further helps organize your code and your data.
We won't be covering that in this video, but it will be in a future lesson.
Let's take a look at how to define a structure.
We'll use the type keyword, followed by the name of the structure, and then finally, the
struct keyword.
We'll have some curly braces, and within the curly braces we'll have our fields.
This field is named field, and it is a type of string.
Here we have an A and a B, and both of those are an int.
So as you can see, this is similar to the function parameters when you write functions.
Let's take a look at how to instantiate a structure.
We'll be working with the sample struct that we just created, and to make one in memory,
we can create a variable, create an assign, use the name of our structure, the curly braces,
and then each field of the structure in order.
We need to make sure that we have the fields in order for this example, because we don't
list the names of the fields.
On the second example, however, we are listing out the names of the field, so they can
be in any order you like, but you would generally want to follow the same order as a struct
itself.
That way, if you make updates, it's easier to change it.
Just like with variables, if you try to create a structure and don't supply any data,
the fields will have default values.
So here on this first example, we're creating a sample structure, and we have curly
braces with nothing in between.
This means that all the fields will have default values.
So the field field will just have an empty string, A and B will both be equal to zero.
It still will be valid to use this sample structure, because default values will populate
when necessary.
On this second example, we're creating another sample structure, and we're setting A equal
to five.
So A will now be five, but field and B will have their default values set.
When we're working with structures, we'll need to be able to access the fields within
the structures, both for reading and writing.
To do so, we use dot notation.
So we'll have the variable name that has the structure, A dot, and then the field name
that we want to access.
In this data example on the bottom, we created a sample structure, and the field is word,
A is one, and B is two.
So if we create the word variable and do the structure name dot field, then this word variable
will contain the word word.
And the same goes for A and B right here, A will be one, and B will be two.
We can modify the structure by reassigning the values.
So we take our data that we created, which is the structure here.
We access the field field, and we use an equal sign and set a new value.
So field will now have hello in it, A will have ten, and B will have twenty.
It's possible to create anonymous or inline structures inside of a function.
This is useful when you're working with library functions or when shipping data across
a network.
What this allows you to do is easily define the data structure where you need it, instead
of having it in a different file or somewhere else across the source code.
Here's an example of some anonymous structures.
To create them, we use the var keyword, just like a variable.
We give it a name, and we use the keyword struct afterward.
We then have our curly braces, and we have our field names, and our types for the fields.
And then we can access it just like we have been using the variable name, and then dot
notation, and the fields that we want to access.
On this second example here on the right, we use the create and assign to create a sample.
We then use the keyword struct, our curly braces, the field names that we want, and then
additional curly braces to define what's going to be in those fields.
So in this example, we have field A and B. Hello, we're going to field.
And then we'll go into A and two will go into B. The main difference between this one
on the left and the one on the right is the one on the left will have default values
if you don't supply any.
So as soon as you create the variable with your var keyword, all of these fields will immediately
have default values, and then later on you can assign them to whatever you need.
The one on the right, however, has to declare these fields and assign them all at the same
time, and you can't be missing any fields.
So when you use the create and assign shorthand, you won't be able to have default values
for any field infrastructure.
Let's recap.
Structures are used to group similar data, and these data points are called fields.
Structures are defined using a type alias with the type keyword.
Fields within the structure can be accessed using dot notation.
Any fields that are not present during instantiation are set to defaults.
In line, anonymous structures can be created within functions.